<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<people>

    <person>
        <name>ALISSON BECKER</name>
      <birthDate>2/10/92</birthDate>
      <placeOfBirth>NOVO HAMBURGO</placeOfBirth>
        <signed>2018</signed>
        <appearances>225</appearances>
      <description>Alisson Becker has cemented his position as one of world football's most formidable goalkeepers since joining Liverpool in 2018. He arrived at Anfield from AS Roma and was integral to the Champions League and Premier League triumphs in 2019 and 2020 respectively. The Brazilian enjoyed an incredible first season on Merseyside after becoming an immediate starter for Jürgen Klopp's side, initially wearing the No.13 shirt. Alisson played every minute of the Reds' domestic campaign and made history when he became the club's first goalkeeper to win the Premier League Golden Glove award in more than a decade after recording 21 clean sheets en route to a second-placed finish with 97 points. The stopper was also crucial in helping Liverpool win the Champions League for the sixth time. He preserved the Reds' spot in the knockout stages of the 2018-19 competition with a crucial late save against Napoli on matchday six.</description>
        <image>ab.jpg</image>
      <webPageURL>https://www.liverpoolfc.com/team/first-team/player/alisson-becker</webPageURL>
    </person>

    <person>
        <name>ADRIAN</name>
      <birthDate>3/1/87</birthDate>
      <placeOfBirth>VEVILLE</placeOfBirth>
        <signed>2019</signed>
        <appearances>26</appearances>
      <description>Liverpool signed experienced goalkeeper Adrian on a free transfer in August 2019 and he played 11 games as the Premier League was won in his debut season. The Spaniard joined the Reds after six years in the top flight with West Ham United, for whom he made a total of 150 appearances before embarking on a new chapter on Merseyside. Adrian – who originally made the move to England from Real Betis – arrived as cover and competition for Alisson Becker following the departure of Simon Mignolet. He took the vacant No.13 shirt previously worn by new teammate Alisson and would have to deputise for the latter almost immediately upon his arrival. Indeed, in the very same week he signed, Alisson sustained an injury in the season-opener against Norwich City at Anfield and Adrian stepped in from the bench. On just his 10th day as a Red, the stopper was the hero when he saved the decisive penalty in a shootout with Chelsea to win the UEFA Super Cup. He continued between the sticks as Jürgen Klopp’s men won each of their opening eight Premier League fixtures to lay the foundations for title glory.</description>
        <image>a.jpg</image>
      <webPageURL>https://www.liverpoolfc.com/team/first-team/player/adrian</webPageURL>
    </person>

    <person>
        <name>CAOIMHIN KELLEHER</name>
      <birthDate>23/11/98</birthDate>
      <placeOfBirth>CORK</placeOfBirth>
        <signed>2015</signed>
        <appearances>20</appearances>
      <description>Caoimhin Kelleher has become a firm part of the Liverpool goalkeeping set-up since joining in the summer of 2015. The Republic of Ireland stopper switched to the Reds from Ringmahon Rangers and progressed through the ranks at the Academy up to first-team duties. Three friendly appearances for the senior side came his way ahead of the 2018-19 campaign, which would end with Kelleher collecting a winner’s medal as an unused substitute when Jürgen Klopp’s team defeated Tottenham Hotspur in the Champions League final. He took further strides in the next season, achieving his Reds debut in the Carabao Cup against Milton Keynes Dons and playing two more games in that competition, producing a vital save in the penalty shootout win over Arsenal at Anfield. Kelleher was also part of the youngest-ever Liverpool team when Shrewsbury Town were beaten 1-0 in an FA Cup fourth-round replay. </description>
        <image>ck.jpg</image>
      <webPageURL>https://www.liverpoolfc.com/team/first-team/player/caoimhin-kelleher</webPageURL>
    </person>

    <person>
        <name>JOE GOMEZ</name>
      <birthDate>23/5/97</birthDate>
      <placeOfBirth>CATFORD</placeOfBirth>
        <signed>2015</signed>
        <appearances>172</appearances>
      <description>A classy defender who can operate anywhere across the backline, Joe Gomez has overcome serious injury setbacks to win a series of major honours with Liverpool. Signed as an 18-year-old from Charlton Athletic in the summer of 2015, he has since featured for the Reds at centre-back, right-back and left-back. Handed his senior debut on the opening day of 2015-16, Gomez sustained a serious knee injury while on international duty with England U21s shortly after Jürgen Klopp’s appointment as manager in October 2015. After a 17-month spell on the sidelines, Gomez returned to action in January 2017 and then made 31 appearances in 2017-18 as Liverpool reached the Champions League final. An outstanding start to 2018-19 was rewarded with a new contract in December 2018, although his progress had been halted by a lower-leg fracture sustained a week before he put pen to paper.</description>
        <image>jg.jpg</image>
      <webPageURL>https://www.liverpoolfc.com/team/first-team/player/joe-gomez</webPageURL>
    </person>

    <person>
        <name>VIRGIL VAN DIJK</name>
      <birthDate>8/7/91</birthDate>
      <placeOfBirth>BREDA</placeOfBirth>
        <signed>2018</signed>
        <appearances>216</appearances>
      <description>Virgil van Dijk is a Dutch professional footballer who plays as a centre-back for Premier League club Liverpool and captains the Netherlands national team. Considered one of the best defenders in the world, Van Dijk is known for his strength, leadership and aerial ability. After beginning his professional career with Groningen, Van Dijk moved to Celtic in 2013. With Celtic he won the Scottish Premiership and was named in the PFA Scotland Team of the Year in both of his seasons with the club, and won the Scottish League Cup in the second. In 2015, he joined Southampton before signing for Liverpool in January 2018 for £75 million, a then-world-record transfer fee for a defender. With Liverpool, Van Dijk reached back-to-back UEFA Champions League finals in 2018 and 2019, winning the latter. He was also named PFA Players' Player of the Year and the Premier League Player of the Season in his first full season. </description>
        <image>vvd.jpg</image>
      <webPageURL>https://www.liverpoolfc.com/team/first-team/player/virgil-van-dijk</webPageURL>
    </person>

    <person>
        <name>IBRAHIMA KONATE</name>
      <birthDate>25/5/99</birthDate>
      <placeOfBirth>PARIS</placeOfBirth>
        <signed>2021</signed>
        <appearances>47</appearances>
      <description>Ibrahima Konate bolstered Liverpool’s defensive ranks when he joined Jürgen Klopp’s team ahead of the 2021-22 season. The France centre-back agreed a move to the Reds from RB Leipzig after four seasons with the Bundesliga club in which he played almost a century of games in domestic and European competition. Konate’s first steps in football came with Paris FC before he joined the academy of FC Sochaux in 2014 and switched from an aspiring striker to the middle of defence. He progressed through the ranks at Sochaux and made his professional debut in January 2017, which was followed by a run of Ligue 2 appearances in the second half of that 2016-17 season. Konate’s promising performances quickly caught the attention of Leipzig and they swooped to sign the defender on a free transfer that summer.</description>
        <image>ik.jpg</image>
      <webPageURL>https://www.liverpoolfc.com/team/first-team/player/ibrahima-konate</webPageURL>
    </person>

    <person>
        <name>KOSTAS TSIMIKAS</name>
      <birthDate>12/5/96</birthDate>
      <placeOfBirth>THESSALONIKI</placeOfBirth>
        <signed>2020</signed>
        <appearances>57</appearances>
      <description>Kostas Tsimikas brought title-winning and Champions League experience to Liverpool when he joined on a long-term contract in August 2020. The Greece international left-back made the move to Merseyside after 86 appearances in all competitions for Olympiacos, with whom he won the domestic title in 2019-20. It was a breakthrough year for the defender, including 46 games – 12 in the Champions League – as his side reclaimed the Greek Super League. Tsimikas had made his debut for Olympiacos in December 2015 and later enjoyed productive loan spells with Esbjerg in Denmark and Willem II in the Netherlands before establishing himself in their first team.</description>
        <image>kt.jpg</image>
      <webPageURL>https://www.liverpoolfc.com/team/first-team/player/kostas-tsimikas</webPageURL>
    </person>


    <person>
        <name>KALVIN RAMSAY</name>
      <birthDate>31/7/03</birthDate>
      <placeOfBirth>ABERDEEN</placeOfBirth>
        <signed>2022</signed>
        <appearances>2</appearances>
      <description>Calvin Ramsay joined Liverpool from Aberdeen on a long-term contract in the summer of 2022. An attack-minded right-back, the Scotland U21 international had risen rapidly through the Dons’ ranks having joined them as a nine-year-old and turned professional in 2019. He was initially a central midfielder, developing his skills in that position until U15 level, when he was suddenly deployed on the right side of defence during a youth tournament. Such was his impressive transition, Ramsay has remained in that position ever since and he graduated to make a senior debut for Aberdeen as a substitute against Dundee United in March 2021.</description>
        <image>kr.jpg</image>
      <webPageURL>https://www.liverpoolfc.com/team/first-team/player/calvin-ramsay</webPageURL>
    </person>

    <person>
        <name>ANDY ROBERTSON</name>
      <birthDate>11/3/94</birthDate>
      <placeOfBirth>GLASGOW</placeOfBirth>
        <signed>2017</signed>
        <appearances>260</appearances>
      <description>Andy Robertson’s rise from amateur football to Premier League and Champions League-winning captain of his country has been nothing short of meteoric. Now firmly established as one of the world’s premier full-backs, Robertson was still playing part-time for Queen’s Park in his native Glasgow as recently as 2013. During his first two seasons with Liverpool - following a transfer from Hull City in the summer of 2017 - Robertson progressed from squad player to key component in a team that followed up reaching the European Cup final in 2018 by winning the tournament while posting a remarkable 97-point domestic season a year later. </description>
        <image>ar.jpg</image>
      <webPageURL>https://www.liverpoolfc.com/team/first-team/player/andy-robertson</webPageURL>
    </person>

    <person>
        <name>JOEL MATIP</name>
      <birthDate>8/8/91</birthDate>
      <placeOfBirth>BOCHUM</placeOfBirth>
        <signed>2016</signed>
        <appearances>185</appearances>
      <description>Matip made his debut on 27 October 2009 in a Regionalliga West match against 1. FC Saarbrücken. He made his Bundesliga debut for Schalke on 7 November 2009 against Bayern Munich, in which he scored the game-tying goal and was subsequently named man of the match. After his successful introduction to the first team, Matip remained a regular starter for Schalke in defensive midfield for the remainder of the 2009–10 season, scoring two further goals against 1. FC Köln and Eintracht Frankfurt. On 2 March 2010, Matip signed a three-and-a-half-year contract with Schalke 04.</description>
        <image>jm.jpg</image>
      <webPageURL>https://www.liverpoolfc.com/team/first-team/player/joel-matip</webPageURL>
    </person>

    <person>
        <name>RHYS WILLIAMS</name>
      <birthDate>3/2/01</birthDate>
      <placeOfBirth>PRESTON</placeOfBirth>
        <appearances>19</appearances>
      <description>Rhys Williams is a commanding centre-half who emerged from the Academy to feature for the Liverpool first team under Jürgen Klopp. Having joined the club as an U10, Williams represented the Reds throughout the age groups before signing his first professional contract in February 2019. In the same season, the defender was a member of Liverpool’s FA Youth Cup-winning squad, with the trophy secured after a penalty shootout victory over Manchester City. Rhys headed out on loan to continue his development in 2019-20, linking up with Kidderminster Harriers in the National League North and making 26 appearances. Upon his return for the next campaign, Williams began to stake a claim at senior level and he was handed a debut in the Carabao Cup tie with Lincoln City in September 2020. And as injuries struck Klopp’s squad, he would gain several more opportunities, featuring in the Champions League and Premier League to help the Reds finish third.</description>
        <image>rw.jpg</image>
      <webPageURL>https://www.liverpoolfc.com/team/first-team/player/rhys-williams</webPageURL>
    </person>

</people>
